<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>

  <journal name="DemocracyDownfall" sidebar_text="Democracy's Downfall recovered"
        chat_text="We have recovered Democracy's Downfall, an ancient ship of great power. Your advisor's response has been noted in the journal."
        full_text="Woah… unbelievable! I thought this great flagship was lost during the four hundredth year of the great civil war! Supposedly, it was lost with all hands during the battle of Narshe. Created by Greenhaven, this Flagship was supposed to be the answer to the Kyr-Sun Empire’s superior fighter class ships. It was also given some experimental engines that let it cut across planet gravity wells with astounding speed. It’s armed exclusively with the G1-SG (generation 1 smart grenade) and their disarming and paralyzing variants.

One of the biggest issues however for Democracy’s Downfall, was that it’s smart grenades were the first generation of them. Unlike our current Gen 5 smart grenades -which are still rather short range mind you,- Gen 1 smart grenades were rather frail, and early attempts at firing them at high speeds tended to damage the internals of the smart grenade, thus resulting in duds very often, and self destruction of the firing mechanism rarely. This necessitated that the launching mechanism fired the G1-SG at a speed less than approximately 200 meters a second, and thus giving it an absurdly short range. However, despite this disadvantage, The Democracy’s Downfall’s speed more than made up for it, allowing the ship to pull off shock and awe tactics against whole fighter squadrons, simply blazing full speed ahead and smashing aside anything in range.

Did you know Democracy’s Downfall wasn’t this flagship’s original name? Before it’s demise at Narshe, it was christened as the GH Protector. It’s assigned general disagreed with the ship’s creators and tried to get them to retire or at least refit the ship to be more “practical” by fitting more standard weapons, citing that its short range would eventually be exploited once the shock factor wore off, but perhaps ironically, His success with the flagship - namely, the victories at Sendal, Jubbul, Norvig (2nd battle) and Lakota- made the ship’s creators refuse to do anything about it, and the supreme general of Greenhaven saw the flagship as a powerful weapon in the right hands, and thus the GH Protector was there to stay. It was during the battle of Narsh - a key planet that had wormholes to many Greenhaven colonies-, when Greenhaven had anticipated an incoming incursion from the Kyr-Sun Empire and scrambled a defense force towards Narsh. It was there where the Kyr-Sun Empire deployed a new prototype weapon, which was able to destroy the GH Protector in a couple of hits, allowing their fighter wings and bomber hordes free reign over the now exposed cruisers and destroyers. After that battle, the Kyr-Sun Empire was able to push deep into Greenhaven territory, and install it’s brutal autocracy upon the colony worlds. The supreme general of Greenhaven gave the nickname Democracy’s Downfall to the GH Protector after he received the news of its demise, as a reminder that nothing is truly invincible.

Erm.. forgive me for ranting Commander, I just tend to go on about our ancestor’s weapons and ships, back when we weren’t forced to make do with whatever we can scavenge for these days. I wonder if we can find any of the other great flagships from the civil war? Anyways, I’ll talk to you again if another one of those great flagships shows up. Alan out."
      />
  <journal name="TheClockwork" sidebar_text="The Clockwork recovered"
           chat_text="We have recovered The Clockwork, an ancient ship of great power. Your advisor's response has been noted in the journal."
           full_text="The Clockwork. A mishmash of metal plates, crudely bolted on turrets, haphazardly structured internals, a ludicrously unstable reactor and a bunch of pirates at the helm. And of course, the giant laser weapon, dubbed the Titan Beam mounted directly onto the bow. According to what I could dig up on the ship, It was a mostly cobbled together ship, held by spit and prayer. Yet somehow, here it is, albeit barely salvageable. If the reactor had gone critical instead of burning all its fuel, I doubt there would be anything left of this hunk of junk. Personally, I would consider this hulk to be obsolete and to scrap it for resources, but the Titan Beam alone is reason enough to repair this thing. While Greorge and I would like to rip the Titan Beam off of the ship, It’s too heavily wired into the Clockwork’s internals and reactor. If we want to use it, we have to repair the Clockwork.

During the civil war, there wasn’t a better time for piracy. With Greenhaven and the Kyr-Sun Empire duking it out against one another, The military of both factions had their hands tied trying to gain the upper hand over their counterpart, which left many a backwater world and even some more prominent worlds ripe for the taking. It was during the civil war that piracy became a major threat to any colonized planets that were not near the front lines. One band of pirates, named Sorrow’s Fang began to rise in notoriety, pillaging many worlds and looting both Greenhaven and the Kyr-Sun Empire’s ships from their shipyards to replace losses. Eventually, after raiding and capturing a Kyr-Sun Empire R&amp;D station, the Sorrow’s Fang’s members were able to discover and haul off the then experimental Titan Beam from the R&amp;D station onto a freighter. Just in the nick of time too, as the Kyr-Sun Empire sent in a whole armada, including an Über class carrier. Despite taking a couple of losses, the freighter and most of her escorts managed to make a jump far away, back into Sorrow’s Fang territory.

The Sorrow’s Fang now had a very powerful weapon. But they needed to power it, and most of their pirate ships are not of the same quality as the ones owned by Greenhaven and the Kyr-Sun Empire. And so they underwent an ambitious project: to build a flagship capable of competing with the likes of Greenhaven and the Kyr-Sun Empire. After jury rigging a reactor to power the Titan beam, the Sorrow’s Fang crudely attached the Titan Beam onto the reactor directly. They then focused on looting outlying industrial worlds for raw materials. After armoring the reactor as much as possible, they just strapped on some turrets and called it a flagship, and the then leader of the Sorrow’s Fang gave it it’s name. The Clockwork would then go on to see plenty of victories against other pirate gangs and militias on civilian worlds, it’s Titan Beam is powerful enough to crack most ships apart if not melt them to slag. It’s reign of terror spanned just over a quarter of the civil war. However nothing lasts forever. Supposedly, the Clockwork would meet its end at the hands of a giant civilian salvage ship. That must’ve been embarrassing! Said salvage ship probably would have scrapped the Clockwork, but by then the AI began rebelling, leaving this desecrated husk floating for us to find.

Perhaps I have bored you with the details of this ship. I really do tend to run my mouth a lot, don’t it? Anyways, The Clockwork is now functional again. We’ve managed to make the reactor more stable, so we don’t run the risk of blowing ourselves up. Unfortunately, while the Titan Beam can hit targets a respectable distance away, the targeting computer can only work if the enemy is nearby. We would’ve liked to increase it’s effective range, but alas, due to its experimental state, we can’t really risk tinkering with it without damaging it. Additionally, it seems like the reactor functions as the ship’s engines and warp drives rolled into one package, and stabilizing the reactor lead to a reduced output, so expect the Clockwork to momentarily lose it’s mobility when transitioning through a wormhole. I wonder… if this is just a pirate flagship, what other great ships could we find? Alan out."
           />
  <journal name="ReprocessorRegnat" sidebar_text="Reprocessor Regnat recovered"
           chat_text="We have recovered Reprocessor Regnat, an ancient ship of great power. Your advisor's response has been noted in the journal."
           full_text="The Gardener of Anud. The Heroic Harvester. The Consumer of Pirates. This Ark goes under many nicknames, most of them given by various pirate gangs active during the civil war. But none were as prominent as Reprocessor Regnat, which is what I shall henceforth refer to it as the Regnat. It’s original name is lost to time, but I do remember it’s purpose. It was once the first generation of colony ship used to travel the void of space before we developed wormhole travel. After setting the colonists down on a planet (I don’t know which one, and the old data banks had been long replaced by up to date ones) it became just a big brick in space, destined to be abandoned and left to drift through the void after its purpose had been fulfilled.

When the civil war broke out, both Greenhaven and the Kyr-Sun Empire began overhauling and retrofitting any and all old ships they had access to. Reprocessor Regnat was no exception. It ended up being in Greenhaven territory and during the two hundred fifty sixth year of the war, it saw use. Not as a combat class ship, but rather a benign salvage ship. The massive former colonist quarters were converted into large cargo bays, hydroponic decks swapped out for massive smelters, refineries and oxidizing fuel and the colonist shuttles were upgraded to (then) modern cargo ships to haul material to and from the Regnat. Additionally, the Regnat was equipped with large, solid iridium harpoons to impale and draw in large chunks of destroyed ships, to be crushed, compacted and divided by a gravity manipulator. Most of the battles during the civil war were massive, sometimes having battleship class ships numbering in the tens of thousands, and all that material had to come from somewhere. After Greenhaven victories over battles, Reprocessor Regnat was called in to salvage as much material as it could. While it wasn’t extremely efficient, it still was responsible for a large amount of raw material and resource flow for Greenhaven, allowing them to constantly produce their battleships, destroyers and cruisers. Something that the Kyr-Sun Empire had trouble with.

Despite the 800 year civil war mostly being about Greenhaven and the Kyr-Sun Empire’s conflict, it wasn’t just those two duking it out. There were pirate gangs roaming about that were looking to pick on certain worlds or ships. And what better time to do that than during war, when both sides's military was occupied? Many worlds, cargo ships and civilian space stations were raided during the civil war. After being chosen as the next target, Reprocessor Regnat was supposed to be another textbook pirate raid. Shoot the engines, demand surrender, loot and scoot. But the crew of Reprocessor Regnat were a scrappy bunch (pun intended). Manning the harpoons, they shot and impaled several pirate frigates, reeling them in like a fish and crushing them with extreme gravity. The pirate fighters and bombers couldn’t do much to dent the thick armor of the Reprocesssor Regnat, and were promptly pulled in by the Reprocessor Regnat’s gravity manipulator and brutally squished. No survivors. Pirates kept attempting to raid the Reprocessor Regnat but they all met the same fate. It wasn’t until a pirate flag ship belonging to the Sorrow’s Fang faction managed to escape the Reprocessor Regnat that it told the grizzly fate of its former mates. Since then, it was widely agreed upon by the various pirate gangs to never again attack that particular ship.

Enough about the past. Maybe I’m getting a bit senile in my old age. The Reprocessor regnat has been upgraded from the derelict hulk it once was. It’s engines have been updated, a shield generator has been installed and it’s gravity manipulator is still as deadly as ever. We also installed a Micro warpgate inside of it to transport metal back to our storage network, so we don’t have to worry about offloading it’s cargo at a command station. In it’s current state, it’s able to “metabolize '' hostile ships, recycling the raw materials for our own use. The boys in R&D think that with enough investment, they can further increase the efficiency of the on board refineries. If we ever do win the war against the AI, I think I’ll spend the rest of my days trying to track down this ship’s original name. Alan out."
           />
</root>
