<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>

  <journal name="DemocracyDownfall" sidebar_text="Democracy's Downfall recovered"
        chat_text="We have recovered Democracy's Downfall, an ancient ship of great power. Your advisor's response has been noted in the journal."
        full_text="Woah… unbelievable! I thought this great flagship was lost during the four hundredth year of the great civil war! Supposedly, it was lost with all hands during the battle of Narshe. Created by Greenhaven, this Flagship was supposed to be the answer to the Kyr-Sun Empire’s superior fighter class ships. It was also given some experimental engines that let it cut across planet gravity wells with astounding speed. It’s armed exclusively with the G1-SG (generation 1 smart grenade) and their disarming and paralyzing variants.

One of the biggest issues however for Democracy’s Downfall, was that it’s smart grenades were the first generation of them. Unlike our current Gen 5 smart grenades -which are still rather short range mind you,- Gen 1 smart grenades were rather frail, and early attempts at firing them at high speeds tended to damage the internals of the smart grenade, thus resulting in duds very often, and self destruction of the firing mechanism rarely. This necessitated that the launching mechanism fired the G1-SG at a speed less than approximately 200 meters a second, and thus giving it an absurdly short range. However, despite this disadvantage, The Democracy’s Downfall’s speed more than made up for it, allowing the ship to pull off shock and awe tactics against whole fighter squadrons, simply blazing full speed ahead and smashing aside anything in range.

Did you know Democracy’s Downfall wasn’t this flagship’s original name? Before it’s demise at Narshe, it was christened as the GH Protector. It’s assigned general disagreed with the ship’s creators and tried to get them to retire or at least refit the ship to be more “practical” by fitting more standard weapons, citing that its short range would eventually be exploited once the shock factor wore off, but perhaps ironically, His success with the flagship - namely, the victories at Sendal, Jubbul, Norvig (2nd battle) and Lakota- made the ship’s creators refuse to do anything about it, and the supreme general of Greenhaven saw the flagship as a powerful weapon in the right hands, and thus the GH Protector was there to stay. It was during the battle of Narsh - a key planet that had wormholes to many Greenhaven colonies-, when Greenhaven had anticipated an incoming incursion from the Kyr-Sun Empire and scrambled a defense force towards Narsh. It was there where the Kyr-Sun Empire deployed a new prototype weapon, which was able to destroy the GH Protector in a couple of hits, allowing their fighter wings and bomber hordes free reign over the now exposed cruisers and destroyers. After that battle, the Kyr-Sun Empire was able to push deep into Greenhaven territory, and install it’s brutal autocracy upon the colony worlds. The supreme general of Greenhaven gave the nickname Democracy’s Downfall to the GH Protector after he received the news of its demise, as a reminder that nothing is truly invincible.

Erm.. forgive me for ranting Commander, I just tend to go on about our ancestor’s weapons and ships, back when we weren’t forced to make do with whatever we can scavenge for these days. I wonder if we can find any of the other great flagships from the civil war? Anyways, I’ll talk to you again if another one of those great flagships shows up. Alan out."
      />
</root>
